renderforest.com 2019-06-01

# Privacy Policy | Renderforest

Welcome to Renderforest’s Privacy Policy.

We’re really glad you are reading this because this information is the best way to understand how Renderforest uses and manages your personal information.

We take your privacy seriously. Renderforest has never sold and will never sell, lease, or exchange your personal data with any third parties in ways other than described in our Privacy Policy.

Renderforest is a company based and operating in Armenia. This policy outlines how we handle your personal information if you’re a Renderforest user or a visitor of our website. We highly recommend that you carefully review Renderforest’s Privacy Policy before engaging in any activity this website has to offer. This privacy policy is a part of our Terms of Service and covers the collection and use of your personal information by Renderforest.

For any questions on our Privacy Policy, contact us at 

[ support@renderforest.com ](mailto:support@renderforest.com)or send a written letter to Renderforest, 27 Azatutyun Street, Yeraz Business Center, Republic of Armenia.

### The Personal Information We Collect

We collect different types of personal information about the visitors and users of our website.

You can either anonymously browse our website, become a signed-up user or a subscriber to one of the Renderforest subscription plans. When you choose to sign up or become a subscriber, we will ask you to provide us with certain personal information so that we can create your account and make it possible for you to use Renderforest services. The required information will include your name and email address. You must provide this information in order to obtain an account and Renderforest agrees not to distribute this information to a third party in ways other than described in our Privacy Policy.

When purchasing a subscription you will be required to provide additional information on your payment and billing details so that we can process the transaction. Such third party processors who use your personal information are governed by their respective privacy policies which may or may not contain privacy protections in this privacy policy.

We also collect data generated when you log in to our website; including, your IP address, the type of device you use to log in to our website, your browser type, and operating system.

At Renderforest you are given an opportunity to sign up via Google or Facebook account. If you choose to sign up through one of these social media accounts we may also receive personal information the provider shares with us. In order to gain full understanding to what kind of information the social media platforms share with us, please refer to the provider’s privacy policy. ([Google Privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [Facebook Privacy](https://www.facebook.com/policy))

The personal information collected by Renderforest may be used to inform you about your purchase or if you want to purchase a certain product. If you have given your consent to send you email newsletters, we may also use this information to inform you about specific services that you may be interested in.

The video projects you create and the media files you upload from your device are saved on your personal media library. Renderforest may permanently delete your personal files after 60 days from your last activity, if you have not made any purchase.

For certain video templates, Renderforest enabled a new feature based on machine learning algorithms and AI principles, which allows Renderforest editor to generate animated stories from video scripts. By using the information from previously created animated videos, the automated system creates a new animation based on a video script. Collecting and processing such kind of anonymous information has no purpose other than to enhance the user experience within the website.

### The Personal Information You Make Public

Your profile and edited videos will be available only to you as a sole user. The videos you created with Renderforest will be available on My Videos page and are marked _unlisted_ by default. That means only people with the link can see your videos. You can make them private if you do not wish anybody else but yourself to have access to them or you can make them available for other Renderforest users to see or share. In this case, we do not accept responsibility for the way they will use that data.

Also, Renderforest provides its users the opportunity to interact and post content through various social media sites. Your interactions with such websites are publicly viewable outside of the website domain. Each social media site has its own privacy policy which may be more or less protected than our policy. If you do not wish for this information to be disclosed, then you should not use these online tools.

Please, think carefully before giving your information to anyone else or making it publicly available.

### The Ways We Collect Your Data 

  * Personal information.
  * We generally collect your personal data directly from you when you provide it to us as in the above mentioned cases.
  * We collect your personal data from third party providers when you choose to login to your account with the help of social media services like Google and Facebook. These websites do not follow the same privacy policy as Renderforest. We recommend that you read the privacy policies of [Google ](https://policies.google.com/privacy)and [Facebook ](https://www.facebook.com/policy)before submitting any personal information. The personal information we get from third party social media services are under your control via your privacy settings on the respective social media accounts and you can change them at any time through the settings of the third party providers.
  * We collect your data automatically when you browse our website. Renderforest may use cookies to improve our website and user experience. This will not, under any circumstances, affect your privacy or data security. Members who disable cookies will not be able to use the service, as they are required to maintain your login to our website within a browser session.
  * Non personal information.

When accessing Renderforest web pages, we may log your IP address; access your URL, time of access, geographic location, browser type, and referral URL in order to identify users who are using the service for spam or other activity that is deemed in conflict with our Terms of Service.

### The Reasons We Collect Your Data

The only reason we collect data from you is to make your Renderforest experience possible and successful for you. The information will only be used in the following situations:

We ask for your name to make it possible for you to create and maintain an account, so you can become a Renderforest user.

We collect your email address to keep you updated with operational news and information about our services and notify you about any significant changes or security updates. Renderforest will send you service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. For example, we will send you an email if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

We collect your data to improve our products and services. We may as well use your information and email address to contact you regarding your inquiry when issuing a customer support request to Renderforest.

If you give us your explicit consent, we will periodically send you emails providing you with marketing information about products and services that might be of interest to you. You have the choice to opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the end of every email newsletter.

If there are any technical problems with unsubscribing, contact 

[ support@renderforest.com ](mailto:support@renderforest.com) and we will willingly solve the issue.

### We Protect Your Information

Renderforest will store all user information in secure databases protected in a variety of industry-standard access controls to assist us in protecting your data. However, no company can fully eliminate security risks associated with the transmission of personal information through online transactions, and you do so at your own risk.

We offer the use of a secure server and implement various security measures to keep the safety of any personal information you submit to Renderforest. All sensitive information (like credit card details) are stored on secure servers that are managed by Renderforest and our service providers. After any transaction, your credit card details and financial information are immediately deleted from our servers.

Renderforest may also employ some safety procedures to help protect your information from loss, unauthorized access, alteration or destruction.

If you have any questions about security measures on this website, please send us an email at 

[support@renderforest.com](mailto:support@renderforest.com) .

### Cookies?

### Yes.

When visiting Renderforest, certain information is being recorded which is generally anonymous information and does not reveal your identity. Renderforest uses cookies to operate our website and improve its user experience. This will not, under any circumstances, affect your privacy or data security. Members who disable all cookies will not be able to use the service, as some of them are essential to maintain your login to our website within a browser session. However you can block or delete them by changing your browser settings at any time. We store such cookies for a period of 30 days, after which the cookies are deleted.

Essential Website Cookies are: 

forest.sid| for user login session identification.  
---|---  
seenTutorial| for knowing whether user has already seen tutorial in our editor or not.  
  
We also use third party advertising companies to advertise Renderforest based on prior visits to our website. For instance, if you visit Renderforest, you may later be exposed to ads for our products when visiting Facebook. Should you wish, you can disable any Renderforest ads from the cookie settings of the third party providers. In this case you will be able to use Renderforest without being imposed to see any of our ads.

Such third party cookies are:

_cfduid| CloudFlare Service cookie for providing security, preventing attacks, mitigating DDoS.  
---|---  
_csrf| for mitigating XSS attacks.  
_ga| Google Analytics for gathering information to understand interactions with our website and refine that experience.  
_ym_isad| Yandex Metrica Cookie for statistics and analytics.  
  
You can modify your browser preferences to accept all cookies or to reject them. If you choose to reject all essential website cookies we will not be able to provide you with our services as it would be impossible to keep you logged in without using them.

### Forms of Disclosure

We do use the services of third party providers to operate our website. These service providers have access to personal information needed to perform such functions on our behalf and authorized to use your personal information to provide these services to us. 

**The services include credit card processings, analytics service providers, customer service, YouTube API services and transactional message delivering companies that we believe are in full compliance with GDPR requirements. As their services require, we may transfer as much of your personal information to them as necessary for them to perform their services. All of our third-party cooperator companies are located in GDPR compliant geographies.**

Apart from third party providers, we may also disclose your personal information in the following situations:

  * Under the specific circumstances where we are authorized or required by law to do so.
  * To respond to requests regarding a criminal investigation or illegal activity.
  * To defend our rights, or to address financial or reputational risks. 

Any disclosure of your personal information will be done to protect your or our company’s vital interests as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us, our subsidiaries, affiliates, employees or agents.

Your personal data will only be used to protect our legitimate interests and will never be provided to other parties for advertising, marketing or other commercial uses without your consent.

### Third Party Providers and Links

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by Renderforest and we encourage you to be aware when you leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information apart from us and our privacy policy.

Renderforest uses YouTube API to control the player directly from the website. This makes it possible for our users to directly publish videos on YouTube. By using this feature of Renderforest services, you acknowledge to be bound by [YouTube Terms of Service ](https://www.youtube.com/t/terms)and [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

In addition to Renerforest's normal procedure for deleting stored data, users can cancel Renderforest's access to their data via [Google security settings](https://myaccount.google.com/permissions?pli=1). If you have any complaints regarding Renderforest’s privacy practices incorporated with YouTube API, contact our Support Team via [support@renderforest.com](mailto:support@renderforest.com)

Renderforest uses Paddle services to process multi-currency payment transactions. This allows our users to pay in their local currency. We believe that all our third party partners are in full compliance with GDPR requirements. However, they may have privacy notices other than described in this policy, so we encourage you to carefully read the privacy notices of every website that collects personally identifiable information. Find more about [Paddle’s Buyer Privacy Notice ](https://paddle.com/privacy-buyers/)here.

Renderforest uses Storyblocks API to make it possible for our users to integrate stock videos into their projects. All the 115.000+ royalty free stock videos are the property of Storyblocks, and Renderforest users are allowed to use these footages without any restriction for as long as they are incorporated into videos created by our users through our video templates.

Renderforest contains links or resources to other websites that are not owned or controlled by our website. These links are not endorsements to these external sites and those websites do not follow the same usage term or privacy policy as Renderforest.

Although we are not responsible for the activities of such third-party sites, we do want to protect the integrity of Renderforest, and would welcome any feedback regarding your concerns about such websites.

### Affiliate Programs and Social Media

Renderforest allows all of its users to participate in any contest or take advantage of any promotion our website has to offer. If you agree to participate in our affiliate programs, contests, and promotions, you acknowledge that you may be obligated to share your personal information with us. Also, if you agree to use our affiliate program, any registered user must acknowledge that s/he voluntarily provided the email address of another person or party. This information can be used to contact and encourage this third party to use our services.

Also, Renderforest provides users the opportunity to interact and post content through various social media sites. Your interactions with such tools are publicly viewable outside of the website domain. Each social media site has its own privacy policies which may be more or less protected than our policy. If you do not wish for this information to be disclosed, then you should not use these online tools.

### Privacy of Children

The services or products of our website are suitable for people who are at least 16 years or older. If you are younger than 16, please don’t give us your personal information or use our website without parental supervision. We comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and encourage parents or guardians to monitor their children’s use of Renderforest.

### Updates in Privacy Statement

This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time to stay up to date with the latest legal requirements.

We will notify you about any significant changes including changes on how we collect or use your personal data, the types of personal information or the purposes for using your personal information via our website. In case of any changes regarding the collection or usage of your personal information, you will be asked to give your consent via email notification.

The latest version of our Privacy Policy will be available on this page. 

### Right to Access

You have a right to ask for a copy of your personal information that we possess at any time. If you wish to do so, please contact us at 

[ support@renderforest.com](mailto:support@renderforest.com) and after verifying your identity, we will provide you with an electronic copy of your personal information as soon as convenient within 72 hours. The only case we will not be able to provide you with such access would be its affecting the rights and freedom of others.

You have full access to any personal information you provide us and you can change or delete it at any time. You can directly change your username by logging in to the website and accessing your profile settings. And you can request our support team to change your email address whenever there is a need to do so. Unfortunately it’s technically impossible for you to do it on your own for now.

### Right to Be Forgotten

If you no longer want us to possess your personal information or to provide you with Renderforest services, you can erase all your personal information by simply deleting your Renderforest account.

Nevertheless, we will retain a part of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests: preventing frauds, resolving disputes and troublesome problems, complying with the law and assisting investigations and other actions permitted by law. (The information will not be retained for more than 90 days).

Note that after deleting your account we will not be able to provide you with our services or restore your account, and if you want to rejoin Renderforest you will need to complete a new registration process.

Know Your Rights

You have a right to lodge a complaint If you think that your right to data privacy has been violated by Renderforest in any way. In this case you need to contact the relevant supervisory authority in your country.
